Between the wind and the lion is the woman. For
her, half the world may go to war.
The Wind and the Lion is a action, adventure,
drama film directed by John Milius.
At the beginning of the 20th century an American woman is abducted in Morocco by Berbers, and
the attempts to free her range from diplomatic pressure to military intervention.
Mulai Ahmed er Raisuli, played by Sean Connery.
Eden Pedecaris, played by Candice Bergen.
Theodore Roosevelt, played by Brian Keith.
John Hay, played by John Huston.
Samuel Gummere, played by Geoffrey Lewis.
Capt. Jerome, played by Steve Kanaly.
The Wind and the Lion is a 1975 American epic historical adventure film written and directed by
John Milius, and starring Sean Connery, Candice Bergen, Brian Keith, and John Huston.
The film is loosely based on the real-life Perdicaris affair of 1904.
Connery plays Mulai Ahmed er Raisuli, a Moroccan Berber rebel and anti-imperialist leader, and Bergen plays
his American hostage Eden Pedecaris, a fictional character inspired by Ion Hanford Perdicaris.
Milius' second feature film as a director, it was produced by Herb
Jaffe for Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, and distributed in the U.S.
by United Artists and internationally by Columbia Pictures.
It received generally positive reviews from critics,
and was a moderate commercial success.
Jerry Goldsmith’s film score received Academy Award,
BAFTA Award and Grammy Award nominations.
Milius was nominated for a Writers Guild of America Award for his screenplay.
The film explores themes of morocco, political
negotiations, historical fiction, desert, colonialism.
The tone is emotional.